它終於開始看起來像一個真正的人類住宅。
接著...
我不認為我可以繼續在我精疲力竭時按下忽略按鈕。
該死的！一個人獨自一人幾乎無法度過一天。
不要在意科學和進步。
要是再多一個實力強大的人就好了……
我已經看中了這個。
就在我複活的地方，
我看到了一個被掃到這裡的人的異常陽剛之手
從和我一樣的方向。
雖然我已經看到了比我想要的更多的這張臉......
已經 3700 年了吧？
嘿，大笨蛋。
接著...
是時候開始使用 Senku 實驗室了。
喲，大笨蛋。
你需要什麼才能像我一樣醒來？
究竟是什麼讓 3700 年前的全人類石化了？
外星人技術攻擊假說
第一...
Dude, earthlings are so lame.
Let's turn them all into stone.
It did work on the swallows.
Petrification Beam!
Lawl, this is exhilarating!
Some Nation's Military Weapon Hypothesis
Number two...
The petrification device is finally complete!
Oh, crap! It backfired!
New Virus Strain Hypothesis
Number three...
We're petrification viruses!
We infect only humans and swallows!
Rofl, this is exhilarating!
The only thing that's certain
is that it targeted humans and swallows specifically.
It seems like some kind of insane fantasy, but there must be some underlying rule.
Which means I can fight it.
Figuring out the rules is the basis of science.
I'm standing in the face of an uncharted branch of science.
This is exhilarating.
Now, think.
How did I get out of my petrification?
Was it just simple deterioration?
如果是變質，暴露的表面不是先壞了嗎？
但石像一路都是石頭。
為我，
當我的其餘部分變回活細胞時，表面仍然是石頭。
正好相反！
表面已經退化到無法恢復為活細胞。
這就是為什麼它變成了一個石殼。
碰巧不那麼石化的表面部分恢復為細胞。
這一定是為什麼殼中缺少碎片的原因。
所以我沒有因為惡化而復活。
有一些特殊的外部因素。
離我頭最近的碎片堆在地上。
這意味著復興是從我的頭腦開始的。
裡面有東西。
這氣味...
硝酸！
我脖子後面的頭髮仍然石化。
讓我們在這根石毛上試試吧。
為什麼我只需要硝酸？
它在 Taiju 或其他人身上一毫米都不起作用。
為什麼？
我和其他人有什麼區別？
思考...
我只需要一個假設。
思考。
思考...
就是這樣！我剛在想！
3700 年來，我一直保持清醒。
大腦一天消耗 400 卡路里的熱量。
超過 3,700 年，這相當於 2 太焦耳。
所有這些能量是從哪裡來的？
E=mc²。
能量和質量有等價交換。
這是愛因斯坦老人推導出來的科學基礎。
根本沒有辦法從無到有產生能量。
為了使用我的大腦，我正在消耗石頭中的某些東西。
這意味著如果我能弄清楚那是什麼，我就可以解除石化。
嘗試一切。
去嘗試一下。
我真的很想嘗試工業蝕刻溶液nital。
該死的。
可惜我沒有酒。
實驗室
相信。
Try, try, try, try, try, try...
And try some more.
Never forget.
Petrification may be a fantasy,
but the foundations of science are absolute.
I need more manpower.
Take the nitric acid and wake up already, you blockhead!
You're awake, aren't you?
You've been awake for the past 3,700 years!
You're no different from me.
You don't know when to give up!
Senku! I...
Taiju...
I'll believe in you and wait for as long as it takes.
I'm hopeless without you!
Come back, Taiju!
Come back, Senku!
It stopped raining.
The thunderstorm that was keeping us camouflaged is gone.
Don't raise your voices.
If Tsukasa hears us, we'll be instantly screwed.
You're right!
He's not coming, is he?
I'm impressed you noticed my neck.
I hardly gave you a speck of a hint.
Taiju, Yuzuriha, you both get ten billion points.
Good morning, world
早安世界！
我走了多遠？
只有腳痛
給我一種距離感
希望在漫漫長夜的盡頭看到美麗的景色
是什麼讓我今天堅持下去
眾神之山，綠之宮殿
洞窟深處，碧空盡頭
我會走完全程，沒有限制
到世界盡頭
早安，世界
早安世界！
擺脫黑暗的不可能
將神話變成日常生活的奧德賽
在這艱辛的旅程中，翻過每一塊石頭
我們將擴大我們的世界
石頭世界的兩個國家
它的...
... 經過 ...
別介意我的頸神經，你剛剛壓碎了我的整個身體！
我會殺了你！
我相信你知道不這樣做，但不要去感謝我的每一件小事。
我也不會謝謝你。
歡迎回來，千空君。
Don't you think the shape on this hide kind of looks like a rocket?
There are star-looking things, too!
They don't look anything like it.
It looks like a science flag. I bet it'll look good on Senku-kun.
Let's put it on his neck, just in case.
Oh, yeah!
It'll be even better with a splint. See?
Uh, I really don't need this.
I'm all better now.
Professor Senku's self-sacrificing human experiment was a success.
The restorative effects of undoing petrification are too damn high.
The petrification that's given us so much grief is what cured you, too, huh?
You said it when we made soap, too...
But maybe this petrification is the stone of life that replaces doctors for us.
It's Doctor Stone!
Come to think of it, it's weird.
When the petrification is undone, it repairs everything around it, too.
What a considerate scientific phenomenon.
I've been thinking this whole time...
Who petrified humanity?
Who attacked us?
No...
Was it really even an attack?
If it can fix Senku-kun's neck,
maybe if we piece together
the shattered statues and pour revival fluid on them, it'll put people back together.
I tried that right at the beginning.
They just went back to being a shattered corpse.
Why wouldn't it work if it's so regenerative?
Yuzuriha...
Taiju's ten billion percent too crude for this.
You're our ultra-skillful crafts club member.
It'll be a grueling mission.
Can you do it?
That really is really grueling.
But I'll do it!
That was quick.
Craft is all about perseverance!
Are you sharing secrets?
No fair! Let me in on it!
I, um... was saying maybe we should go see Tsukasa-kun.
Oh, yeah?
Tsukasa's place, huh?
What?!
Why?!
He's the dangerous man that killed Senku!
I mean, he's not dead, and he was a good guy, but...
At the very least, he thought he'd killed Senku!
That's exactly what we accomplished in that fight.
Tsukasa thinks I'm in the afterlife now.
Meanwhile, I can always know where Tsukasa is.
We'll have a giant advantage in this battle,
if you two can infiltrate the Tsukasa Empire as spies.
I gave Yuzuriha the details about the mission.
Taiju, you protect Yuzuriha.
Blockheads like you are better off not knowing everything.
All right, I got it.
I'll do it.
Tsukasa intends to use the miracle water,
revival fluid, to amass an army of young people to make a new world ruled by military might.
In order to defeat the Tsukasa Empire
and stop the mass destruction that is the purification of humanity...
我們必須建立一支革命軍隊，可以利用科學與他們作戰。
但是你自己怎麼做呢？
是的。
如果杉菜有神奇的水，硝酸，你就不能製造火藥，
而且你不能增加你的人力。
答案是顯而易見的。
我要找到發射煙霧信號的神秘人
讓他們站在我這邊。
問題是他們可能會先遇到Tsukasa。
我只能打賭他們沒有的機會。
所以，往後，我們二人將成為司庭帝國的間諜。
您將為科學革命軍隊尋找盟友。
我們每個人都會打自己的仗。
這就是想法。
想到我們悲傷的告別，我都淚流滿面。
你們倆都太隨意了。
伙計們真的很堅忍，對吧？
是的。
Senku 總是合乎邏輯的。
我們有一段時間不會見面了。
不是幾週，幾個月，甚至……
陰影！
我保證——”
等等，我不能提高我的聲音。
在我離開的那一小會兒。
嘿，你已經等了 3700 年了。
再多幾個月或幾年沒什麼大不了的。
我們要建立我們的科學王國。
右後，57 米。
是的，你，就是過去兩分鐘一直默默關注我的人。
你是誰？
藍眼睛。
她年輕。
太巨等人剛剛把她復活了？
或者還有其他方法可以讓人們復活嗎？
現在，這不好。
你不應該先說“很高興認識你”嗎？
閉上你的嘴！
保存您對地獄的介紹。
不可能的。
她還太年輕，沒有這種能力。
武術界不可能沒有聽說過她。
她是誰？
我看到了一切！
你劫持了一個女人，
然後你無情地殺死了那個為她挨打的紳士。
我聽不見你在說什麼，
但我對你的背景不感興趣。
向巫師紳士懺悔，直到你的靈魂腐爛！
巫師？
你剛剛沐浴在它裡面，你已經忘記了嗎？
你用可疑的黑火藥在召喚山之怒火！
山之怒火？
火山爆發？
因此，您可能不是複活者中的一員，而是他們的孩子之一。
或者...
你是哪一代？
她是一個沒有科學的純潔原始人。
我可以輕鬆地統治他們。
我可以輕鬆殺死他們。
沒有理由攻擊他們。
因此，我的直接目標是返回洞穴。
Taiju 和 Yuzuriha 已經看到瞭如何製作火藥。
我需要在他們之前取得奇蹟之水。
這是再見。
You're... the sorcerer gentleman who protected that woman.
You're alive!
Stop talking.
You can introduce yourself all you want later.
Don't waste your energy.
Can you hold out until evening?
If you're at your limit,
I'll take a gamble and blow it up with the little gunpowder I have left.
But if you can hold on,
it'll take forever, but I'll save you, ten billion percent.
You're the only one who can make the decision!
Decide right now!
Which is it?
Yeah, my organs and bones are all fine.
I can hold on.
I'd say the fallen tree weighs roughly one ton.
To get it to one side would take half of that, 500 kilograms.
Assuming my own weight is just over 60 kilograms,
multiplied by 2 to the 3rd power to get to 500 kilograms...
I can just barely make it with three.
Maybe I don't know what to do
Hurry up, my mind is on the moon
The bamboo's barely strong enough.
Flying up to where the wind blew
I'll just have to pack them with dirt.
In my hands awakens
The passion overflowing
Just wandering through this world
Who would have thought that soap would be so useful now?
Your one shining pure
Could never be pierced with a rusty knife
It's an all-star team of Great Professor Senku's inventions.
I'm burning like a fire gone wild
The moment an arrow shot through my heart
The noise plaguing me was released
What is this?
Everything was different from that moment on
This is science.
If I don't try, I'll never know
It was invented by Old Man Archimedes a few hundred years BC.
Why do flowers bloom?
It converts the measly strength of a high school kid into Herculean might.
Your voice echoes
It's called a pulley!
Tell me why?
I just shouted to the sky
But you are no no no longer here, that's right?
The life we confirmed that day
You can call it a fleeting dream if you want
But I'll save you from a wounded today
Amazing.
No, I'm not talking about that Archi-whoever's wisdom.
I'm talking about your unwavering diligence in forcing yourself through every step
until you solve a problem.
My name is Kohaku.
It seems I've taken quite a liking to you.
Two Nations of the Stone World
Next Episode
Where Two Million Years Have Gone
這是一部虛構的作品，但所描述的植物、動物和生產方法都是基於現實的。自行覓食和製作東西是極其危險的，在某些情況下也是非法的。沒有專業知識的請不要模仿。